So now let's talk about Amazon Q Business.
So Amazon Q Business is a fully managed Gen AI
assistant for your employees.
What does that mean? Well, we have an assistant,
but it's based entirely on your company's knowledge and data.
So here, this is a very specific use case where Gen AI is for your company,
and it's trained on your internal data.
So for example, what can you ask Amazon Q Business?
Well, you can say, write a job posting for a senior product manager role,
where we have, of course, this role being very relevant to whatever our company is doing,
or create a social media post under 50 words to advertise the new role,
or for example, what was discussed during the team meeting in the week of the 4-12.
And so, of course, all of this cannot be answered by a general foundation model.
It needs to be a model that has been trained on your own internal data.
With the right security, of course.
So as a whole, Amazon Q Business can answer questions,
provide summaries and generate content and automate tasks,
as well as perform routine actions, such as, for example,
doing self, such as submitting timer request, or sending meeting invites.
Behind the scene, Amazon Q Business is built on Amazon bedrock,
but we have less control so we cannot choose what is the underlying foundation model.
And actually, Amazon Q Business is built on multiple foundation model from Amazon bedrock.
So this is a service that's a little bit higher level,
geared toward a very specific use case, of using and exposing your company internal data
from an LLM genii perspective.
So here's an example, we're saying, what is the annual total out-of-pocket maximum
mentioned in the health plan summary?
So this is for our company, we're in the medical space.
And we have a company document, a PDF, that has the very answer.
And so Amazon Q Business is able to look up that document,
look at what the document says, and then we give us the answer in our chats,
similar to rag, of course.
And then, of course, we will have a sources section where we say, hey, the sources of
this is the health plan PDF document, and you can click on it and find it right away.
So let's have a look at a diagram to better understand Amazon Q Business.
So here it is.
We have first some data connectors.
So data connectors are fully managed rag, and you can connect to over 40 popular enterprise
data sources.
So you don't have to learn about them all, but it's good to see some of them.
So we have Amazon S3, where we can store data files onto AWS.
It's a very popular service.
We have Amazon RDS, it's a database service.
We have Aurora, another database service, and work docs a service used specifically for
documents on AWS.
And then we have non AWS services, such as Microsoft 365, Salesforce, Google Drive,
Gmail, Slack, SharePoint, etc, etc.
And the idea is that Amazon Q Business will have built-in integrations with these services,
and then once the integration is made, then it will crawl these sources
and do what it's supposed to do to allow you to search them and query them.
Next, we have also plugins.
So before data connectors was about retrieving data and understanding what is the knowledge
inside of our company, but next we have plugins and plugins allow Amazon Q Business
to actually interact with third party services.
For example, we have zero, service now, Zendesk, Salesforce, etc, etc.
And the idea is that, for example, if we say to Amazon Q Business,
hey, create a Jira issue, this is to create a ticket so we can track a problem in our company,
then Amazon Q Business will leverage the plugin and automatically create that Jira issue for us.
So on top of reading data, Amazon Q Business has the ability to create and move data in your
company as well.
And you can extend it because you can create custom plugins to connect to any third party
application using APIs.
Now, how do we access Amazon Q Business?
Well, our users are going to be authenticated through something called IAM Identity Center.
So I am the center is a way for users to log in and we'll see how.
And then once user are logged in, then they will only have access to the documents
to should have access to.
So by using your whole company data with Amazon Q Business, you still have the certainty
that someone with less privilege will not be able to access all your documents.
Otherwise, that would be, of course, a big security risks.
So here we have IAM Identity Center and our users are going to log into it by just having a
signing box where you enter a username and a password and you go to go.
And then you have what's called an authenticated user with its own permissions because I am an
Identity Center knows what the user is able to access or not.
And then the user can ask questions to Amazon Q Business, which is a web application.
And of course, access only the documents it should have access to.
On top of it, you can integrate IAM Identity Center with what's called external identity providers
or IDP. And it could be, for example, a Google login or a microsoft Active Directory and so on.
And so that means that instead of logging in and getting an AWS-based signing page,
you're going to log in with a system where users are already created.
For example, it could be your Active Directory where you have your microsoft login or it could be
your Google login. For example, if you're using the G Suite type of workspace for your company.
So this is very handy and it's really going hand in hand with whatever security systems you have in
place in your company. Next, we have admin controls. So these are controls used to customize
responses based on what your organization needs. So admin controls are pretty much the exact same
thing as guardrails in Amazon bedrock. So, for example, if we have a blocked topic such as gaming
consoles and our employees asking, hey, how can I configure a brand new Nintendo Switch, then you're
going to use the Amazon Q Business is going to say, well, this is a restricted topic. So we can
block specific words or topics and we can also choose for Amazon Q to respond only with internal
information versus using also external knowledge. So if we specify it to only use internal
information, then only your company documents will be used to respond to a query. If not,
then we have access to the broader knowledge of the foundation model. You can also make sure to
set up these admin controls either on the global control global level. That means for all type of
topics and all type of subjects or you can set up more specifically at a topic level. So you have
more specific admin controls, but they are the same as just at what level do you want to apply them?
So that's it for Amazon Q Business. I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.